Let's open these data sets in a Jupyter Notebook.
I downloaded the CSV files and put them in the same directory as this notebook.
So like we did in the last lesson,
we can read the data sets with pandas read_csv and the file name as a parameter.
What's going on here?
All the data was read into one column,
and it looks like the values are separated by semicolons.
Sometimes, CSV files use different characters to separate their values.
We can choose the correct delimiter by setting this additional parameter in read_csv.
By default, this parameter is set to
a comma which is why we don't normally have to specify this.
Cool. It's normal to mess up the first time you read in a CSV file.
For example, if you didn't know that there wasn't a header line in a CSV file,
you'd first incorrectly use the values in the first line as
a column labels and then realize you need to
specify parameters to set your own column labels.
Alternatively, you can inspect the file yourself.
One way of doing this is by opening it in
a text editor or a spreadsheet program like Google Sheets.
But if you're working with large data sets,
this might take a long time to load or crash a program.
For this scenario, trial and error in pandas would be the better option.