To analyze our data more efficiently,
let's combine the red and white data sets into one data frame.
Before we do this, we need to add a new feature or column
to each data frame that indicates whether the wine is red or white.
This way we will preserve this characteristic
for each sample when the data frames are combined.
One way we can do this is by creating an array using
NumPy and add that as a column into each data frame.
Let's learn about NumPy and how we can use it to do this.
NumPy is short for numerical Python and is designed for efficient scientific computation.
It's built on top of the programming language C
which works at a lower level on our computer.
To understand what this means for the speed
of our code, see the link in instructor notes.
Pandas is built on top of NumPy
which is why it's so fast with all these computations for functions like Describe.
If you try doing these computations in plain Python, it's much slower.
Here's an example, calculating the mean for an array of 100 million values.
This generates an array of 100 million random floats between zero and one.
We could also type in 1e8 to make this clear.
Looks like that provide the float when it requires an int.
Let's see how long it takes standard Python to compute the mean of this array.
Okay, so a little more than 9 seconds.
Now let's see how long it takes NumPy.
That is almost instant.
Isn't that cool? Imagine how much it speeds
up the process when there is much more computation happening.
For example, let's say we are engineering
a whole new feature or column which you compute by
multiplying the values in two columns
together and divide by the values in another for each row.
Unlike NumPy, plain Python will require
a massively long loop through all the rows to compute a new value for each row.
The main object we work with in NumPy is
a multi-dimensional array of values of all the same data type.
These arrays, along with many useful functions in NumPy,
optimize and simplify operations on data.
You'll learn more about NumPy arrays later.
In the next section,
you'll use NumPy to create an array for
a new color column for the red and white data frames.