Group By is one of my favorite functions in pandas.
It let's you group your data and aggregate information about
those groups or perform group specific transformations.
In this section, we'll focus on using GroupBy to
get summary statistics about different groups in our data.
Let's open the combined wine quality data frame we just created.
Previously, we learn that we can get summary statistics
on the whole dataset with functions like describe or mean.
From this, I can find information like the mean pH for all the samples in the data set.
But, what if I wanted to find the mean for each quality rating?
For example, the mean pH level for all samples of the quality rating of seven.
We could use groupby combined with the mean function to do this.
With this, we can find the mean pH level for
all samples with a quality rating of seven here.
We could even split the dataset with multiple columns to groupby,
by providing a list.
These are means of all of the other features grouped by quality and then color.
Here, we see separate means for the pH level of
all the red and white samples with a quality of seven.
If you don't want quality or color to be made as the index,
you could set as_index to false.
If you're only interested in one of the columns,
like the pH, you could index the groups like this.
Next, you'll learn groupby to draw some conclusions about this dataset.